Bitter Lake is a documentary film directed by Adam Curtis.
An experimental documentary that explores Saudi
Arabia's relationship with the U.S.
and the role this has played in the war in Afghanistan.
Narrator, played by Adam Curtis.
Self (archive footage), played by George H. W. Bush.
Self (archive footage), played by George W. Bush.
Self (archive footage), played by Joanne Herring.
Self (archive footage), played by Ronald Reagan.
Bitter Lake is a 2015 BBC documentary by British filmmaker Adam Curtis.
It argues that Western politicians have manufactured a simplified
story about militant Islam, turning it into a good vs.
evil argument informed by, and in a reaction to, Western society's increasing
chaos and disorder, which they neither grasp nor understand.
The film makes extended use of newsreels and archive footage, and intersperses brief
narrative segments with longer segments that depict violence and war in Afghanistan.
The film explores themes of politics, manipulation,
manipulation of the media, control, fear.
The tone is mind_bending.